Welcome to CREST. A group of users
can collaboratively search for and
book a property to live in using CREST.
Ayala, Miguel and Nick will be using CREST
to find a place in New York for the summer.
CREST addresses several challenges
There are no tools that provide both
collaborative search and agreement support. So
Ayala, Miguel and Nick will have to
use three or more different tools:
Airbnb to search, chat and email to
share their findings and a google
spreadsheet to keep track of their preferred
properties, budgets and terms and conditions.
Sometimes their efforts might feel
discontinuous and it is difficult
to coordinate remotely and asynchronously.
Without a clear goal-oriented
process, team members can waste
time exploring properties that might not
contribute to the overall team’s needs.
It is difficult, even among friends,
to find ways to negotiate or work
around conflicting preferences.
Only one in the group can
effectively book for the team;
stripping the other members of their ability
to explicitly agree or disagree to a property.
CREST and its friendly mediating now addresses
all of the aforementioned challenges.
Crests supports the main actions involved in group
property-booking: search,
discussion and agreement.
Hi im Ayala and I'm from kazakhstan. I'm really
excited to be living with two of my best friends
this summer in New York City. I'm a junior
architect studying the empire state building
so I would need to be within walking distance of
it, but I can only afford 300 dollars per month.
Hi im Nick, i'm a linguistics graduate student
and I am enrolled in a coding intensive bootcamp
this summer in New York City. All I need is a
place to stay during the night and sleep and I
am a really good cook, so I can cook for rent, but
my monthly budget is only 150 dollars per month.
Hello I'm Miguel and I live in Mexico City. I
really care about shopping and living in style.
For me the most important thing is to have my
own bathroom and a very, very clean kitchen.
I've been saving up for this trip and I think I
can afford to spend around 600 dollars a month.
Miguel starts using CREST, sets his budget
to 600 dollars, and he then adds Wi-Fi,
Kitchen, and Cable TV as preferences.
Ayala sets her budget to 300
dollars and adds being close
to the Empire State Building as a preference.
Ayala explores the properties in the search
results lists by looking at some images.
These properties can be sorted
by relevance, price, or ratings.
Users receive messages from CREST-Bot, our
automated mediation agent, in many places in the
app, like the property item and the chat. These
carefully curated interventions derive inspiration
from legal mediation literature and rely on data
collected from our Collabo-ratio visualisation,
which tracks three key collaboration metrics:
activity, influence and communication. In fact,
Ayala leverages a CREST-Bot message to
encourage Nick to participate in the task.
Ayala finds a nice property for the group that is
close to the Empire State Building and
decides to propose a contract for it.
The contract contains the terms and conditions
of the team’s stay. Ayala leverages a CREST-Bot
notification so that she and her team can reach
the desired budget. Once that takes effect,
she proceeds to sign the contract and
sends a message to her group about it.
Nick sees Ayala mentioning him in
the chat and proceeds to add his
preferences. He notices Ayala’s property
is a bit too pricy and proceeds to a near
metro preference so that Ayala can take
the metro to the Empire State Building.
Nick uses this new metro preference to look
for a cheaper alternative and finds one
thanks to a CREST-bot notification, which
he uses to propose a new contract for it.
Nick starts working on the contract by
also leveraging CREST-Bot interventions
on matters of budget distribution and
house rules creation. Nick offers to
cook for everyone in the team but notices a
CREST Bot notification saying that he should
take out the apartment’s trash every week.
Since he is paying very little for rent,
he accepts this recommendation. He signs the
contract and then updates the team in the chat.
Miguel logs in at some other time, and notices
several contracts proposed. He sees that
Ayala’s contract is ranked very low and sees a
CREST-Bot notification saying that this contract
doesn’t satisfy one of his preferences. He then
sees that the contract proposed by Nick is highly
ranked and is even recommended through a CREST-Bot
notification, which he uses to open the contract.
Miguel likes this contract and likes the fact
that he is paying less than his original budget.
He sees a CREST-Bot recommendation telling him
to create a house rule to justify him being the
one paying the most for the team. He uses it to
make things better for him and signs the contract
Ayala sees that her original contract is
low in the ranked list and that two of
her teammates have signed the contract for
a property near the metro. She also sees
that CREST-bot is encouraging her to take
a look at this contract, so she opens it.
She adds a few house rules to justify the daily
habit of taking the metro and signs the contract.
Now that they all signed and agreed on a property,
the team can proceed to have fun in new york city.